{
    "id": "868c49be119048649dd66b8c17ebe3a0",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "That is not ………………… the color I wanted.",
            "description": "Not quite can mean not exactly.",
            "answers": [
                "quite",
                "quiet",
                "rather"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You eat ……………… too much.",
            "description": "Rather can modify comparatives and too.",
            "answers": [
                "rather",
                "quite",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My mother would rather we …………….. to each other any more.",
            "description": "After would rather, we use a past tense with a present or future meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "don't talk",
                "won't talk",
                "didn't talk"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I will go and see the Prime Minister himself if I have to.",
            "description": "When words like himself, herself and themselves are used to mean ‘that person and nobody else’, it is used as an emphatic pronoun.",
            "answers": [
                "Here himself is used as an emphatic pronoun.",
                "Here himself is used as a reflexive pronoun."
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will never forget the day ……………… my daughter was born.",
            "description": "When can mean on which.",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "on which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "This is Ms. Malini ………………. last year.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun acts as the subject or object of the relative clause. It replaces words like he, him, her etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "who you met",
                "whom you met",
                "whom you met her"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………… money he has comes from his wife’s family.",
            "description": "The sentence ‘What money he has…’ means the same as ‘The money that he has…’",
            "answers": [
                "What",
                "That",
                "Which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They saved hundreds of refugees, ………………… had been at sea for several days.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of whom some",
                "some of whom",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He turned the radio down ...................... he wouldn’t disturb the old lady downstairs.",
            "description": "So that suggests a cause and effect relationship. ",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "so as to",
                "in order to"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A lot of social problems ……………. caused by unemployment.",
            "description": "If the noun following ‘a lot of’ is plural, the verb is also plural.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I will lend it to you on condition that you ……………… it back tomorrow.",
            "description": "In subordinate clauses we often use the present tense to refer to the future",
            "answers": [
                "will bring",
                "bring",
                "would bring"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It doesn’t matter what you .................... with your time or money.",
            "description": "Present tenses are common after expressions like it doesn’t matter and I don’t care.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "does",
                "have",
                "will do"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}